<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Clint Simon</title><link>https://csim.github.io/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Clint Simon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csim.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It doesn't matter what it is. Start Now.</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-10-30-start-now/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-10-30-start-now/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s funny, I put off writing this post for over a week. That might make me a hypocrite but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that the truth is less important. Procrastination is the enemy.
If you want to get something done, start immediately and fail often.
There are a million reasons not to start right away. Maybe you won&amp;rsquo;t be any good at it, or you have more important things to do. Maybe you are just plain scared of judgment from your peers.</description></item><item><title>Good Addictions</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-10-07-good-addictions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-10-07-good-addictions/</guid><description>Ever since I can remember I have been an addict. Over the years my addictions have come and gone. But one thing has always remained: I have an addictive personality. Luckily for me all my addictions have been mostly productive.
It started when I got my first computer, the Commodore 64. At the age of 10 I got the C64 for Christmas and soon after I learned the BASIC programming language so that I could study my Spanish vocabulary words.</description></item><item><title>What my guitar taught me</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2011/2011-02-27-what-my-guitar-taught-me/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2011/2011-02-27-what-my-guitar-taught-me/</guid><description>It turns out that my guitar taught me a valuable lesson. Somehow in this crazy house that I live in, ago a week ago, my guitar spontaneously migrated out of my office. One of the kids moved it to the upstairs bonus room without my knowledge. I usually keep my acoustic guitar right next to my work desk. It sits there 99 percent of the time. Occasionally when the mode strikes, I pick it up and strum a tune.</description></item></channel></rss>