<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clint Simon</title><link>https://example.com/</link><description>Recent content on Clint Simon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 02:01:58 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evolve the product toward complexity</title><link>https://example.com/posts/2016-evolve-complexity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 02:01:58 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/posts/2016-evolve-complexity/</guid><description>Managing a product is hard. Ideas come from all angles, many of them have merit and worst of all you don’t generally have enough direct feedback to make an informed decision about which ideas carry the most value.
There is an inherit danger in committing resources toward too many fearures. Time is finite and the team is small. Picking the wrong features means potentially confusing users or failing to attract users in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Big data == Small privacy</title><link>https://example.com/posts/2015-big-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 17:01:58 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/posts/2015-big-data/</guid><description>I have noticed over the course of the last few months that each time I made an online purchase, miraculously advertisements for a related product appeared in my Facebook feed. Once I didn’t even make a purchase on Amazon but only viewed the product — low and behold that exact product appeared in my Facebook feed. I am not a conspiracy theorist or a privacy freak but this is getting a little creepy.</description></item><item><title>Moving the mountain, again.</title><link>https://example.com/posts/2014-mountain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 02:01:58 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/posts/2014-mountain/</guid><description>Managing a product is hard. Ideas come from all angles, many of them have merit and worst of all you don’t generally have enough direct feedback to make an informed decision about which ideas carry the most value.
There is an inherit danger in committing resources toward too many fearures. Time is finite and the team is small. Picking the wrong features means potentially confusing users or failing to attract users in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Data Migration is Hard</title><link>https://example.com/posts/2013-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 02:09:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/posts/2013-migration/</guid><description>Data migration can sink your project. It lurks around the edges of your estimation model, hiding deep dark secrets that will only be uncovered at the very end of the project. Nothing could be worse. Discovering that you need to increase the migration schedule 5 fold at the 11th hour can not only derail your project but if it happens too often it might derail your career. I have learned a few lesson on this topic: Re-estimate your migration scope of work when there are significant changes in the new application.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://example.com/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/pages/about/</guid><description>In the novel, The Strange Case of Dr. Jeykll and Mr. Hyde, Mr. Poole is Dr. Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s virtuous and loyal butler. Similarly, Poole is an upstanding and effective butler that helps you build Jekyll themes. It&amp;rsquo;s made by @mdo.
There are currently two themes built on Poole:
Hyde Lanyon Learn more and contribute on GitHub.
Setup Some fun facts about the setup of this project include:
Built for Jekyll Developed on GitHub and hosted for free on GitHub Pages Coded with Sublime Text 2, an amazing code editor Designed and developed while listening to music like Blood Bros Trilogy Have questions or suggestions?</description></item></channel></rss>