<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Links on Clint Simon</title><link>https://csim.github.io/tags/links/</link><description>Recent content in Links on Clint Simon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csim.github.io/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Link Roundup</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-20-link-roundup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-20-link-roundup/</guid><description>Microsoft employees getting free Surface tablets, new work PCs, Windows Phone 8 Quite a company meeting this year.
Intel researchers put WiFi inside - the processor, that is Makes sense. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating that analog components in almost all mobile phones.
Japan Commits to Eliminating Nuclear Power Remember when nuclear power was the future? Mother nature issued a veto.
iOS 6 review Love these &amp;ldquo;just the facts&amp;rdquo; reviews.
Will Science Someday Rule Out the Possibility of God?</description></item><item><title>Link Roundup</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-15-link-roundup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-15-link-roundup/</guid><description>Windows 8: The Boldest, Biggest Redesign In Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s History Fast company with a mostly positive article on Windows 8. Refreshing.
The iPhone 5 Is Completely Amazing and Utterly Boring I could not agree more. As Louis CK would say &amp;ndash; Everything is amazing and nobody is happy.
The power of ignoring mainstream news When I first started ignoring news, I felt that I was simply making an excuse, that if I had more time I should read the news.</description></item><item><title>Link Roundup</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-11-link-roundup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-09-11-link-roundup/</guid><description>Never Forget The attacks resulted in the death of 2,996 people, including the 19 hijackers and 2,977 victims. The victims included 246 on the four planes (from which there were no survivors), 2,606 in New York City in the towers and on the ground, and 125 at the Pentagon. Nearly all of the victims were civilians; 55 military personnel were among those killed at the Pentagon.
Sorry, Windows 8 Is Not Going to Save the PC Industry Another article bashing Windows 8 and the Microsoft strategy around it.</description></item><item><title>Link Roundup</title><link>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-07-23-link-roundup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://csim.github.io/posts/2012/2012-07-23-link-roundup/</guid><description>My Favorite Features: Entity Framework Code First and ASP.NET Web API Great overview of the EF5 release with summary and coding samples.
Jason Zander:
New features in Entity Framework 5:
Enum support is a long awaited feature for EF and allows you to have enum properties in your domain classes. EF5 makes enum support available in the EF Designer and Code First. Table-valued functions in an existing database can now be included in models that are created using the EF Designer.</description></item></channel></rss>